## Marcin Brysiak

### Sales and Marketing

### Summary

Innovation Leader. Innovation, Sales and Marketing Advisor for companies. Internet Marketing & Mobile Industry Expert, Initiator and Creator of Web and Mobile products, Project & Sales Manager, Winner of several start-up competitions.

He started his professional career in the telecommunication industry in 2004, however since 2011 he's been creating technology start-ups and contributing to their development (web services and products, mobile applications) and managing other projects in the telecommunication and banking industry. An innovative and unconventional look at business enabled him to develop a number of his own initiatives and others supported through the involvement of strategic partners. He has excellent knowledge of the mobile services market, technology and sales.

He has held various managerial positions and managed projects for several years, and is now supporting business and corporate social responsibility sectors. He is responsible for strategy and sales policies, and relationship building with business partners in numerous projects (Orange, Plus, Play, T-Mobile, Link4, BP, Motointegrator, HTC, Samsung, Multikino, Lotos) who are willing to engage in his innovative undertakings.

He sees the most important value in business, in addition to the constant search for/of innovative solutions, as the effective communication with his team, co-workers, business partners and customers, based on quality and trust.

Cooperated with companies: Kratki.pl, Netia JSC., Telekomunikacja Polska JSC., PKT.pl, PKO JSC. (Inteligo), Sky Cash Poland JSC, Locon Ltd., NAVIEXPERT and created numerous internet products and applications: mymeetingrooms.pl, Sky Cash, mobiParking, odbierz.to, NaviExpert, Korkosfera, Gdzie Jest Dziecko, Gdzie Jest Auto, Bezpieczny Dom, fordrivers.pl

Graduated from several universities: Polish Open University, Warsaw School of Economics, University of Warsaw, Warsaw University of Technology.

### Experience

# Business Development Manager at SentiOne January 2018 - Present

SentiOne is the leading social media monitoring company in Central and Eastern Europe. Our mission is to develop next-generation social listening platform. We help global and local brands track consumers opinions in social media and deliver valuable insights. We work with a few hundred cutting-edge marketing departments from companies like: Procter&Gamble, Unilever, Beiersdorf, Tesco, Starcom, Mindshare, Mediacom or Saatchi&Saatchi.

As the founder I am mainly responsible for the vision and technical side of the company.

Engineering team recruitment, planning and managing software development and deployment process, implementation of key algorithms, operational supervision of critical modules.

We started the company with 200k EUR in seed funding. Thanks to our great team we were profitable after 18 months. In 2016 we raised 3,5 mln EUR Series A funding to scale our business globally. Stay tuned!

### Deputy Director of Marketing at Kratki

December 2016 - June 2017 (7 months)

- Drafting and implementation of marketing strategies.
- Planning and implementation of the marketing budget of the Enterprise and of the subordinate department.
- Drafting marketing plans for new products.
- Building the Enterprise brand promotion strategy and supervision of the achievement of goals.
- Observation of market trends and translating them into operational measures of the enterprise.
- Coordination of works in connection with the Company's participation in trade fairs and other promotional events.
- Monitoring and analysis of the competition's activities and introduction of modifications to marketing activities of the Enterprise.
- Cooperation with market research entities in order to identify and satisfy clients' needs.
- Planning Enterprise activities in connection with the exposition of products in the sales network.
- Management and organization of work of the subordinate team.

### E-commerce expert at Kratki

April 2016 - December 2016 (9 months)

Marketing strategies:

- Business and marketing analyses
- Setting development directions for on-line marketing
- Building new tools and processes of e-commerce sales
- Co-creation of UX/UI
- Maximization of marketing conversion (off-line and on-line channels)
- Optimization of Internet sales processes
- Building price strategies
- Creation of multi-plane marketing campaigns
- Development of web and mobile applications
- Implementation of marketing automation tools

Project management:

- Close cooperation with the IT department in implementing changes
- Managing project budgets

- Coordination of teamwork
- Setting tasks and KPIs
- Cooperation with external suppliers

Selected accomplishments:

I have implemented e-commerce solutions that broke the downward trend in the e-commerce channel (increase of sales results by 100%. Turnover in Q3 > PLN 1 million, YTY increase of 1.9%, September 24.7%, October 102%).

I built from scratch and implemented the company's Contact Centre, which significantly improved communication with clients.

I managed the NrD social campaign, which was to raise public awareness and initiate legislative works aiming to exclude wood from resolutions on countering smog.

I created the requirements for information architecture in mobile devices.

I am creating an interdisciplinary B2B4C strategy, merging communications with various client segments

#### Founder at forDrivers

February 2014 - September 2016 (2 years 8 months)

I would like to describe you our innovative solution- mobile application for Drivers. Why is it so revelatory? for Drivers is safe driving navigator. for Drivers is an application, which promotes safe driving through gamification- head 2 head or in a group. Our application brings together gamification and opportunity to gain prizes and discounts. Its role is to promote wise behaviours behind the wheel. for Drivers give also informations about traffic, roadworks, weather conditions and convenient rest stop. Our users can gain valuable and prizes- new car, smartphones, cameras and attractive discounts. for Drivers cooperate with credible companies- Fiat Auto Poland, HTC Corporation, Motointegrator( proffesional car service stations with more than 5000 points of sale), Multikino( the second largest multiplex chain in Poland), and many, many more. We would like to create international community of resonable and wise drivers, we know how essential it's nowadays to educate people. Due to that reason we are present really often in polish media. Below some random articles about for Drivers:

http://grywalizacja24.pl/grywalizacja-motywacja-do-bezpieczniejszej-jazdy/

http://www.fpiec.pl/startupy/2015/08/27/jakaplikacja

http://www.polskieradio.pl/42/273/Artykul/1478597,Nowy-startup-znalazl-sposob-napiratow-drogowych

http://www.biznes.newseria.pl/komunikaty/it\_i\_technologie/fordrivers\_partnerem\_link 4,b559966023 https://soundcloud.com/adamiukzientarska/testujemy-aplikacje-fordrivers?

utm source=soundcloud&utm campaign=share&utm medium=facebook

http://tech.wp.pl/kat,130058,title,Aplikacja-ktora-moze-uchronic-kierowcow-przed-utrata-prawa-jazdy,wid,17855825,wiadomosc.html?ticaid=115e01

http://mojafirma.infor.pl/moto/technika-jazdy/bezpieczenstwo/727727,Jak-dziala-aplikacja-forDrivers.html

http://www.focus.pl/czlowiek/czy-technologie-mobilne-zwieksza-bezpieczenstwo-na-drogach-blog-12812

### Marketing and Sales Director at Locon Sp. z o.o.

October 2014 - April 2015 (7 months)

We are a software development company specializing in the creation of individual systems for corporate and institutional customers. Our solutions are created by a team of industry professionals, telecommunication and surveying.

We are a leader in the field of location-based services (Location Based Services) and services based on GSM and GPRS technologies using MMS, SMS and WAP. We specialize in services to increase the sense of security, using the latest technology and location monitoring.

Products and implementation realized by Locon gained recognition and meet the expectations of our customers. The quality and novelty solutions can provide a number of awards and distinctions at prestigious events, as well as the high evaluation and recognition products among individual customers.

Our leading products include:

Where is the child - locator available via SMS, web and mobile application that allows parents to know the whereabouts of their children http://www.gdziejestdziecko.pl/

Family Safety - an innovative and unique service Location and Communication in Europe available in the form of applications installed on the phone of the person localized, allowing you to send SOS alerts when threats

http://www.bezpiecznarodzina.pl/

Safe house - monitoring for home or office available via a mobile application and web service http://www.bezpiecznydom.pl/

Where Is Auto - Car locator with alarm functions. http://www.gdziejestauto.pl/

Vice President of the Board, Strategy and Business Growth Director at SkyCash June 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Developing applications and implementing new functionalities.

Acquiring business partners and working with Orlen, Multikino, Kino Atlantic, PKP, city halls, banks, payment providers.

Managing marketing campaigns aimed at increasing the number of users.

# Advisory Board - Strategy and Business Growth Director at My Meeting Rooms May 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Online reservation service for business and meeting space to work.

The project was recognized at the conference 10za50za10 http://www.10za50za10.pl/index.php? page=aktualnosci where from among 20 finalists received a grant of 50 thousand PLN for 10% stake in the company.

### Advisory Board - Strategy and Business Growth Director

May 2012 - September 2014 (2 years 5 months)

Developing a concept as well as implementing and developing http://odbierz.to/

Building a large database in 6 months (3 million unique users).

Achieving profitability within 6 months of the website's launch / sales: approx. PLN 480k/

Acquiring a strategic investor.

#### New Business Sales and Marketing Director at NaviExpert

December 2011 - August 2012 (9 months)

### Deputy Added Products Director (e-commerce, mobile applications) at pkt.pl

November 2010 - November 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Developing an original project - "Print Rewolucja": development of a website and mobile application for pkt.pl's phone book.

Developing HOT LEAD management procedures - transfer of online leads to a call centre responsible for sales.

Developing business cases for a voucher distribution application (innovative on the Polish market).

#### Project Manager – project assignment at Inteligo Financial Services S.A.

May 2010 - August 2010 (4 months)

Developing the pay-by link product (paying using Inteligo and iPKO)

# E-Commerce Sales Manager, eSales Manager, New Sales Channel Development Manager at Netia 2008 - 2010 (3 years)

Increasing sales in the e-commerce channel compared to other channels at Netia S.A. from 7% to 14%.

## Regional BBE (Broadband Everywhere) Programme Coordinator, Sales Coordinator at TP Customer Service

2004 - 2008 (5 years)

Regional Sales Coordinator in charge of the BroadBand Everywhere Programme Sales Coordinator
Sales Representative

### Education

Polish Open University
Master's degree, E-Business, 2010 - 2013
Warsaw School of Economics
Internet Marketing, Online Marketing - Postgraduate studies, 2008 - 2009
University of Warsaw
Sales Management, Postgraduate Management Studies, 2006 - 2007
Warsaw University College of Technology and Business
Engineer, Engineer of Computer Scientist, 2002 - 2006
SGH Warsaw School of Economics

## Marcin Brysiak

Sales and Marketing



Contact Marcin on LinkedIn